Guide to the Jay and Si-Lan Chen Leyda Papers TAM.083
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Jay Leyda Papers, 464819
  - Subseries B: Correspondence, 80251
    - Sub-subseries 1: Alphabetical, 80317
      - Kamin, Martin, 1939-1949; 80486 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Karaganor, Alexander & Bella, 1969-1976; 80485 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Kazan, Elia, 1966-1984; 80484 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - King, Carol; 1930s-42, ca.1930-1942; 80483 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1933-1971; 80482 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Klaue, Wolfgang and Herbert Volkmann, 1964-1974; 80481 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Kleiman, Naum & Bella Epstein, 1942-1979; 80480 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Klein, Jerome, 1935; 80479 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Kleiner, Arthur, 1966-1979; 80478 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Knepler, Georg & Florence; c.1969-85, ca.1969-1985; 80477 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Knight, Arthur, 1947-1958; 80476 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Koch, Howard & Anna, 1944-1986; 80475 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Kozintzev, Grigori & Valentina, 1969-1984; 80474 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Kracauer, Siegfried, 1941-1965; 80473 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Kuleshov, Vladimirovich Lev & Alexandra Sergeyvna, 1965-1966; 80472 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Landler, Ed, 1970-1985; 80471 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Lang, Fritz, 1970-1976; 80470 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Langlois, Henri, 1956-1965; 80469 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Lavy, Nikita, 1978-1985; 80468 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Lary, Nicky & Diana, 1979-1986; 80467 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Lavrova, Nadia, 1939; 80466 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Lawder, Standish D., 1964-1971; 80465 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Lawrence, Jacob, 1941-1975; 80464 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Lawson, John Howard, 1937-1977; 80463 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Leab, Daniel J. & Kathy, 1964-1980; 80462 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Leacock, Richard, 1941; 80461 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Le Chamois, Jean-Paul (Dreyfus), 1946-1966; 80460 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Ledoux, Jacques, 1959-1974; 80459 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Legg, Stuart, 1964; 80458 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Leiser, Erwin, 1964-1974; 80457 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Lerner, Irving, 1933-1978; 80456 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Levin, Harry, 1942-1970; 80455 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Levy, Julien-Jean, 1933-1979; 80454 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Leyda, J.M. (mother), 1930-1943; 80453 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Leyda, Mary Ann, 1944-1977; 80452 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Lippincott (Breit, Harvey), undated; 80451 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Lomax, Alan, 1968-1969; 80450 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Losey, Joseph, 1934-1974; 80449 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Losey, Mary, 1941; 80448 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Lowery, Margaret, 1957-1962; 80447 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Lowry, Malcolm, 1950-1951; 80446 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Luddy, Thomas - Pacific Film Archive, 1973-1978; 80445 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - MacGreen, Bob, 1945-1950; 80444 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Maddow, Ben, 1972-1979; 80443 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Maddow, Ben, 1980-1988; 80442 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Maddow, Freda & Emily, 1956-1970; 80441 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Malthete - Melies, Madeleine, 1963; 80440 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Maltz, Albert; c. 1930-72, ca.1930-1972; 80439 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Marker, Chris, 1969; 80438 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Marshall, Herbert, 1969-1986; 80437 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Martin, M., 1983-1984; 80436 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - "Masses & Mainstream", 1948; 80435 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - McCorkle, Tom, 1971-1974; 80434 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Mekas, Jonas - Anthology Film Archives, 1961-1980; 80433 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Merritt, Russell, 1978; 80432 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Metzner, Erno & Grace, 1937-1965; 80431 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Meyers, Sidney & Edna, 1940-1974; 80430 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Micciche, Lino, 1980; 80429 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Michelson, Annette, 1973-1984; 80428 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Milano, Paolo; c. 1938-49, ca.1938-1949; 80427 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Miller, Trudy & Nick Doob, 1971; 80426 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Mills, Truman, 1932-1939; 80425 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Montagu, Ivor, 1935-1985; 80424 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Murray, Harry A., 1977-1979; 80423 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA), 1935-1983; 80422 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Myrdal, Jan, 1968; 80421 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - National Academy of Television Arts & Sciences, 1979; 80420 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Napoli, Nicholas, 1943-1959; 80419 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Neuman, J.B - New Art Circle, 1925-1960; 80418 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Newhall, Beaumont, 1940-1971; 80417 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Newhall, Nancy, 1942; 80416 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - New Theatre Magazine (Herbert Kline & Leo Hurwitz), 1934-1937; 80415 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Ning, Ma, 1983-1984; 80414 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - O'Konor, Louise, 1966-1969; 80413 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - O'Leary, Liam, 1965-1985; 80412 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Olson, Charles, 1942-1952; 80411 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - O'Neill, James E., 1934-1979; 80410 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Oppenheim, David, 1985-1986; 80409 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Opler, Charlotte Fox, 1966; 80408 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Panofsky, Erwin, 1936; 80407 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Parker, Hershel, 1968-1982; 80406 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Payne, Robert, undated; 80405 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1957-1968; 80404 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Perretta, Vanda, 1967; 80403 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Perry, Ted, 1972-1987; 80402 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Pershing, Margaret Jane, 1961-1963; 80401 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Piscator, Erwin, 1965; 80400 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Platt, David, 1987; 80399 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1947-1948; 80398 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Prentice [Prentiss?], undated; 80397 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Princeton University Press, 1944-1945; 80396 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Rau, Jack, 1930-1977; 80395 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Ray, Man, 1936; 80394 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Ray, Satyajit, 1968-1972; 80393 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Reece, Jean, 1934; 80392 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Renoir, Jean, 1969; 80391 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Richie, Donald, 1965; 80390 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Richter, Hans, 1943-1980; 80389 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Robinson, Lee, 1977-1980; 80388 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Rockefeller, Abby, 1933-1939; 80387 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Rodakiewicz, Henwar, 1940-1970; 80386 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Rosenheimer Jr., Arthur; c. 1940s-62, ca.1940-1962; 80385 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Rotha, Paul, 1935-1964; 80384 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Rowe, L. S., 1940; 80383 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1937-1970; 80382 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Ruttenberg, Joseph, 1986; 80381 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Sadoul, Georges, 1942-1979; 80380 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Sano, Seki, 1939; 80379 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Schmidt, Paul, 1983; 80378 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Schwarz, Josephine, 1930-1988; 80377 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Seagull Books, 1983-1986; 80376 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Sealts, Merton, 1986-1988; 80375 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Sekeroglu, Sami, 1967; 80374 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Seldes, Gilbert; late 1930s - 1940s, ca.1930-1940; 80373 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Sembene, Ousmane; c. 1977, ca.1977; 80372 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Sen, Mrinal, 1975; 80371 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Seton, Marie; 1940s-1978, 1940-1978; 80370 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Sewall, Richard, 1959-1984; 80369 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Sewanee Review, 1948-1950; 80368 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Shrub, Esther, 1960-1969; 80367 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Siegmaster, Elie, 1944; 80366 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Sitney, P. Adams, 1978; 80365 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Smith, Margaret, 1930-1966; 80364 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Smith, Robert, 1939-1940; 80363 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Smyth, James, 1930-1976; 80362 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Sontag, Susan, 1969-1972; 80361 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Soviet Embassy, 1943; 80360 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Soviet Russia Today, 1938-1939; 80359 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Speaker, David M., undated; 80358 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Stieg, William; 1941?, ca.1941; 80357 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Steiner, Ralph, 1934-1941; 80356 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Strand, Paul, 1948-1974; 80355 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Strasberg, Lee, 1934-1942; 80354 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Strick, Joseph, 1965-1976; 80353 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Thompson, Virgil, 1983-1985; 80352 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Thorndike, Andrew & Annelie, 1964-1979; 80351 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Topolski, Felix, 1966-1968; 80350 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Trachtenberg, Alan, 1985-1987; 80349 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Trauberg, Leonid, 1978-1981; 80348 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Tretyakova, Olga, 1965; 80347 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Tuchman, Mitch, 1971; 80346 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Van Druten, John, 1927-1937; 80345 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - VanDyke, Willard, 1984-1986; 80344 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Viazzi, Glauco, 1954-1955; 80343 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Vidal, Gore, 1970; 80342 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Viertel, Salka, 1954-1978; 80341 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Viking Press, 1958; 80340 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Vincent, Howard P, 1964; 80339 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Ward, Theodora, 1957-1970; 80338 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Weinberg, Herman & Annie, 1948-1983; 80337 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Weiss, Peter, 1961; 80336 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - Welch, Norval, 1978-1979; 80335 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - Whiting, F. A., 1938-1941; 80334 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - Wilder, Thornton & Isabel, 1959-1974; 80333 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - Willett, John (The Times Literary Supplement), 1969; 80332 (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - Williams, Carlton - re: 'Thoughts at Nighttime' by Louis M. Eilshemius, 1982; 80331 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Williams, Jane, 1966-1985; 80330 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Wilson, Edmund, 1959; 80329 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Wittenburg, 1940; 80328 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - World Film News, 1936; 80327 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Wyler, William, 1943; 80326 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Yale University Press - Art History, 1968-1979; 80325 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Yale University Press, 1957-1970; 80324 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Yang, Gladys, 1965-1974; 80323 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Yeh, Marcelia, 1963-1980; 80322 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - York University, 1972-1978; 80321 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Young, Kathleen Tankersley, 1930-1932; 80320 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Young, Vernon, 1958-1966; 80319 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Zanussi, Krzysztof, 1960-1961; 80318 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Chronological, 80252
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1930-1933; 80316 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1934-1936; 80315 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1937-1938; 80314 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1939; 80313 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Chronological Correspondence; c.1940s-50s, ca.1940-1959; 80312 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1940; 80311 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1941; 80310 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1942; 80309 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1943; 80308 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1944; 80307 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1945; 80306 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1946; 80305 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1947; 80304 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1948; 80303 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1949; 80302 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Chronological Correspondence; c. 1950s, ca.1950-1959; 80301 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1950; 80300 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1951; 80299 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1952; 80298 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1953; 80297 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1954; 80296 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1955; 80295 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1956; 80294 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1957; 80293 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1958; 80292 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1959; 80291 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Chronological Correspondence; c. 1960s, ca.1960-1969; 80290 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1960; 80289 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1961; 80288 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1962; 80287 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1963; 80286 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1964; 80285 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1965; 80284 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1966; 80283 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1967; 80282 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1968; 80281 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1969; 80280 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Chronological Correspondence; c. 1970s, ca.1970-1979; 80279 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Jan - July, 1970; 80278 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Aug - Dec, 1970; 80277 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1971; 80276 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Jan - May, 1972; 80275 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Jun - Sep, 1972; 80274 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Oct - Dec, 1972; 80273 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Jan - Jun, 1973; 80272 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence, July - Dec, 1973; 80271 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1974; 80270 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1975; 80269 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Chronological Correspondence - Holiday Correspondence, 1975-1979; 80268 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1976; 80267 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1977; 80266 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1978; 80265 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1979; 80264 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1980; 80263 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1981; 80262 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1982; 80261 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Jan - Sep, 1983; 80260 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Chronological Correspondence, Oct - Dec, 1983; 80259 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1984; 80258 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Chronological Correspondence Christmas cards, 1985-1988; 80257 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1986; 80256 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Chronological Correspondence, 1987; 80255 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Undated Correspondence, 80254 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Unidentified & Undated Correspondence, 80253 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - 2016 Accretion: Correspondence and Memorial Ephemera, 1983-1988 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Subseries C: Cinema, Chinese, 80227
    Subseries C: Chinese Cinema contains Leyda's clippings, correspondence, film scripts and research notes, and a typescript of his book Dianying; an account of films and the film audience in China (1972).
    - Article on Chinese film by Jay Leyda and others, 1960-1963; 80250 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chinese cinema - research notes, undated; 80249 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Chinese cinema - research notes; 1960s, ca.1960-1969; 80248 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Dianying" book cover & blurbs, 1970; 80247 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Dianying" Chinese film scripts, 1975; 80246 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Dianying" correspondence; 1950s - 70s, ca.1950-1979; 80245 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Dianying" editorial & research notes, undated; 80244 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Dianying" editorial & research notes; 1950s -60s, ca.1950-1969; 80243 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Dianying" editorial & research notes, 1968-1970; 80242 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Dianying" editorial & research notes, 1970; 80241 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Dianying" editorial & research notes, 1975; 80240 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Dianying" introduction, 1975; 80239 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Dianying" typescript 1, 1963-1973; 80238 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Dianying" typescript 2, 1963-1973; 80237 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Dianying" photographs by Jay Leyda, undated; 80236 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Dianying" proposal, undated; 80235 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Dianying" research clippings; c. 1965, ca.1965; 80234 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Dianying" reviews, 1972-1973; 80233 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Dianying" unidentified typescript fragment, 1978; 80232 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Film Script "Actress" (by Chen Lee aka Jay Leyda), 1961; 80231 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Film Scripts by cinema writers, 1975; 80230 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Notes & correspondence in Chinese, undated; 80229 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Publishers Weekly" publishers' mission to China & related materials in Chinese, 1979; 80228 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Cinema, Soviet, 80156
    Subseries D: Soviet Cinema contains writings, related research notes and clippings, reviews, and some correspondence documenting Leyda's lifelong interest in Soviet cinema and the work of his mentor and sometime collaborator, Sergei Eisenstein. Some are in Russian. There are articles written under the pseudonym James Lincoln for the Moscow News, 1932-36, other articles on Soviet cinema and on Sergei Eisenstein, and letters to Eisenstein. For The Film Sense there are reviews and correspondence. For Kino, there are partial typescripts, reviews, and research notes. There is an unpublished book-length typescript "Letters from Russia" consisting of a selection of letters spanning several centuries. Also included are the research and lecture notes for his reconstruction of Eisenstein's Que Viva Mexico. Shorter Leyda writings include book introductions and reviews, film festival and exhibition catalogs, including an early MOMA film festival, and an editing proposal for Potemkin.
    - Articles by James Lincoln (aka Jay Leyda), 1932-1936; 80226 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Articles on Russian Film by Jay Leyda (published and unpublished); c. 1934 - c.80, ca.1934-1980; 80225 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Dovzhenko, Alexander Patrick - Biography, 1939; 80224 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Eisenstein: articles on, 1972-1978; 80223 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Eisenstein: Award for "Alexander Nevski" (typescript by Jay Leyda), 1938; 80222 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Eisenstein, letters to, 1933-1935; 80221 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "Eisenstein at Work" (book proposal), 1981; 80220 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Eisenstein - Biography: introduction to "Life of Eisenstein" by Ion Barna, undated; 80219 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Eisenstein chronology, undated; 80218 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Eisenstein: "Lessons with Eisenstein" book reviews (transl. by Igor Montagu & Jay Leyda), 1962; 80217 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Eisenstein material in Russian, undated; 80216 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Eisenstein newspaper clippings, 1936-1978; 80215 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Eisenstein notes (by Leyda?), undated; 80214 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Eisenstein notes & drafts; c.1930s - 68, ca.1930-1968; 80213 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Eisenstein, Sergei: The Complete Retrospective of the Museum of Fine Arts," Boston, lecture & notes by Jay Leyda, 1977; 80212 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Eisenstein, Sergei: "Programme for Teaching the Theory and Practice of Film Direction" - 42 pp., 1937; 80211 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Film script "Mission to Moscow" - Jay Leyda revisions to, 1942-1943; 80210 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Film proposal "Girl from Moscow", undated; 80209 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Film Sense" book reviews, 1942; 80208 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Film Sense" correspondence, 1942; 80207 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Film Sense" dust cover, 1942; 80206 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Film Sense" mailing list, 1942; 80205 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - History of Russian film (notes), undated; 80204 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Ivan the Terrible" Part I notes by Jay Leyda, 1944-1945; 80203 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Kino" another introduction, 1971; 80202 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Kino" book reviews; 1960?, 80201 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Kino" dust covers, undated; 80200 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Kino" editorial notes; c.1962, ca.1962; 80199 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Kino in the Modern World" by Karagonova in Russian, undated; 80198 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Kino" notes; 1930s-40s, 1930-1940; 80197 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Kino" notes, drafts, undated; 80196 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Kino" Postscript for Hungarian edition, undated; 80195 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "Kino" preparatory articles by Jay Leyda (Hollywood Quarterly), 1946; 80194 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "Kino" reference notes in Russian, 1931-1942; 80193 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Kino" revisions, undated; 80192 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "Komsomol Truth" (B. Meadow, Michael Rosenfeld), 1935; 80191 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Kozintsev, Grigory "A Child of the Revolution" (article); c. 1951, ca.1951; 80190 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Kuleshov, Lev "Our First Experiences" (article), 1934; 80189 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Letters from Russia" typescript by Jay Leyda 1, undated; 80188 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Letters from Russia" typescript by Jay Leyda 2, undated; 80187 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Letters from Russia" typescript by Jay Leyda 3, undated; 80186 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Letters from Russia" typescript by Jay Leyda 4, 1946; 80185 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Letters from Russia" notes & correspondence, undated; 80184 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Meyerhold, Vsevolod (articles on and by V. Meyerhold), 1949; 80183 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Mission to Moscow" correspondence, 1942; 80182 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - MOMA: Film series, 1939; 80181 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - MOS film work agreement, 1935; 80180 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Moscow Film Festival (typescripts by Jay Leyda), 1965-1970; 80179 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Moscow/Warsaw Film Archives" - a report, undated; 80178 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "New Soviet Movies" New Theatre Soviet Issue (compiled by Jay Leyda), 1935; 80177 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - New York Herald Tribune: "The Study of Russia in the United States", 1944; 80176 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Russian Cinema; 1960s, 80175 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "Potemkin" actor Alexandrov Gregori V. (in Russian), undated; 80174 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Potemkin" editing proposal, 1942; 80173 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Potemkin" score - Arthur Klein, 1967-1970; 80172 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Program: 60 Years of Soviet cinema (in Russian), 1979; 80171 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Que Viva Mexico" complete synopsis Experimental Cinema 5, 1934; 80170 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Que Viva Mexico" fragments, undated; 80169 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Que Viva Mexico" reviews, 1957-1967; 80168 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Russian film seminar (notes), undated; 80167 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "Russian Music" (Sheet Music/Scores), circa 1930; 464947 (Box 32)
    - Shub, Esther, undated; 80166 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Some People of Modern America" by Jack Chen - Moscow (review of Leyda's photo exibit of the same title) & exhibition program in Russian, 1934; 80165 (Box 21, Folder 12)